JEN MCPHAIL

Contact:

516-512-0023 mcphail.jen@gmail.com San Francisco, CA

www.jenmcphail.com

www.github.com/jenmcphail

Profile

A full-stack web developer with experience in marketing, communications and startups in the tech industry.

Skills

Front End Dev: HTML - CSS (SASS, Bootstrap, Materialize) - JavaScript (JS, JQuery, Angular)

Back End Dev: Node -Express - Ruby - Rails -Sinatra - MongoDB - SQL

<u>Design:</u> Adobe Creative Suite - Wireframes - Sketch

Other: Digital Marketing - Digital Marketing - Client Maintenance - Team Management (Agile) - CMS (Drupal, Word Press, Tumblr)

Web Dev Apps

- Browser Games:
 - <u>Tic Tac Unicorn T-Rex</u> and <u>Hangman</u>: Built using front JS, JQuery, and DOM manipulation.
- <u>BuffyWiki</u>: Created a *Buffy The Vampire Slayer* themed app during a one-week sprint. Users can CRUD characters from the show. Technologies used were: Ruby, the Sinatra, framework, and postgresql on the backend, and HTML / ERB, AJAX, and CSS / Bootstrap on the front end.
- Foodly: Worked in a team of 4 to produce a Ruby on Rails app that
 matches users with restaurants in the area. I built the database structure
 and implemented the Stripe API to handle payments and monthly
 subscriptions.
- <u>pisdashio:</u> Developed a personal dashboard web app that aggregates user customized content including weather, news, and a traffic report. I implemented the MEAN stack to handle user auth and routing on the back end and several AJAX API calls on the front end.

Experience

Student, Web Development Immersive, General Assembly, San Francisco

May 2016 - August 2016

Completed a 12-week intensive program to move from a coding hobbyist to a full-stack developer. Built fully-responsive web apps in solo and group settings using Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, and many other frameworks and technologies.

Account Manager, Codeword, New York, NY February 2015 - April 2016

Drove content program activities, including content creation, activations, strategic initiatives and measurement. Communicated between clients and internal teams to own process steps, and all client reviews, feedback, and final delivery.

PR Intern, Burt Greener Communications, Edinburgh, United Kingdom September 2014 - November 2014

Worked alongside Account Executives in the areas of media relations, event planning, creative pitching, and client maintenance. My focus was social media marketing where I successfully grew our client's following on Facebook by over 1000 likes.

Tech Specialist, Student Computing Services, Hofstra University August 2013 - August 2014

Assisted Hofstra University students, alumni, and faculty in navigating Hofstra's IT system and campus network.

Education

- General Assembly Web Development Immersive, May 2016 July 2016
- Hofstra University, BA Public Relations, September 2011 August 2014